Mary Kathryn Olsen

(803) 261 - 6009 · CHATTANOOGA, TENNESSEE

MARYKATHRYNOLSEN@GMAIL.COM

SUMMARY

Creative Developer with 5+ years experience working in fast-pace environments specializing in design, visual communication and e-Commerce. Proven skills in all aspects of the e-Commerce platform ranging in scale from small start-ups to large corporations. Expert skills in project management, multi-level collaboration and meeting deadlines.

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript , JQuery , Bootstrap, Git, GitHub, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe InDesign

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer Olsen Development

July 2017 - Present Chattanooga, TN

- Create beautiful, interactive, responsive websites for small companies using HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript plugins.
- Create branding materials using Adobe Creative Suite.
- Assist companies in maintaining creative assets such as images, logos, and content.

Freelance Product Manager & Developer MK Olsen Designs

Feb 2017 - Present Jackson, WY and Chattanooga, TN

- Collaborate with multiple brands during a single season and build trend analysis specific to each brand
- Provide briefs and coordinate materials for merchandising using InDesign
- Guide in-house teams to finalize product merchandising leading to accurately curated eCommerce concepts

Product Developer & Line Manager Stio Mountain Designs

Aug 2014 - Feb 2017 Jackson, WY

- Researched trend data in product, fabric and industry to identify opportunities
- Maintain SKU master database
- Built clear and concise visual merchandising materials in Adobe InDesign
- Reversed 2 month timeline delay with streamlined production calendar resulting in on-time deliverables and met deadlines
- Implement back-end product line software, Backbone PLM
- Utilize Magento to maintain accurate style count and SKU markup on web

EDUCATION

Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree, Udacity CS50x Certificate, Harvard University BS in Psychology, College of Charleston